Thank you, Lord Jesus. So the
month of August, I don't know
how it has been for you, but for
me it's been one of the best
months this year. Hallelujah!
It's been very eventful.
Indeed, we brought in the
sheaves. And don't worry, first
Sunday of September you hear
mind-boggling testimonies. And
even though your testimony is
not part of it yet, you can
still lay hold. That might— this
might test— I'm testifying on
Sunday. Glory to God! Glory to
God! God has indeed done great
and mighty works amongst us. He
has done it. Hallelujah! I know
the best part of this— prophetic
word does not expire. It does
not expire. So it means that
even from this month till
December, we are bringing in the
sheaves. We are bringing in the
sheaves. Say, I'm bringing in
the sheaves. Glory to God! So in
case you are saying in your
hearts God, me too. God, when?
I want to also testify. Don't
worry, be encouraged, be
encouraged. Glory to God, be
encouraged. You are bringing in
the sheaves. No, the man of God
declared that this month is the
month of bringing in the
sheaves, and he has helped us to
lay foundation. You would see
that the man of God has
systematically laid foundation.
He has helped us to build
infrastructure. And you know
what the Bible says in Isaiah
54? It says, 'Lengthen your
stakes, strengthen your cord,
expand, make room.' What he's
saying is, 'Build infrastructure
for what I'm about to do in your
life.' Hallelujah! Build
infrastructure, because God is
not a God of waste. So he sends
instruction first before his
harvest. He says, 'Strengthen.
I'm not going to pour into
something that does not have the
capacity to carry.' Lengthen
your stakes, strengthen your
cord, expand, make room.
Hallelujah! That's what the man
of God has been doing. He has
taught us on wisdom, mercy,
favor. Glory to God! I hope you
know that the strength of
material is very pivotal to what
is going to enter your life.
The strength of material. When
Dangote was going to, you know,
build a refinery and he knew
that was going to bring
heavy-duty machineries, He built
his own road. He built the road
that can carry it. So heaven
wants to carry heavy duty,
heavy duty ideas, heavy duty
blessings through your life,
but you don't have capacity.
There's no infrastructure. So
you are praying, you are
praying, oh God, and you are
asking for what you don't have
the capacity for. God is not a
God of waste. He's not a God of
waste. So you will not get it.
It's not like you will not get
it in the sense of you not get
it, but he doesn't waste.
That's why he sent his
instruction first. Hallelujah,
hallelujah, hallelujah.
So your strength of material
matters— you've not built solid
infrastructure by praying.
Bible says build up yourself in
your most holy faith, praying in
the Holy Ghost. So prayer is how
we build. You build by praying.
You just come to church on
Sundays, amen, always amen.
Hallelujah! But you don't have
infrastructure. Heaven is
waiting, the angels are waiting.
Oh yeah, now we want to send
this thing, we want to send this
thing. Your road is not even
tarred. You don't have a
consistent prayer life.
Hallelujah! You've not built
solid infrastructure through the
word of God. The only time you
open your Bible is on Sunday and
you are trusting God for the
harvests. There's wisdom,
there's wisdom to these things.
There's something called
spiritual intelligence.
Hallelujah! Build infrastructure
through prayer. Build
infrastructure through God's
word. Find it. What has God said
concerning harvest? Find it and
meditate on it. Read it. Put
your heart to it. Amen. You are
trusting God for healing,
trusting God for— how many
scriptures do you know about
healing? How many scriptures
have you meditated on? You want
breakthrough? How many
scriptures? Because God is not
saying he's not going to give
you. But he needs
infrastructure, spiritual
infrastructure. Glory to God,
glory to God, glory to God.
Infrastructure through
obedience, not selective
obedience. For some of us, God
is our Savior, but He's not our
Lord. Who is the Lord? Someone
you say, yes, sir, to. Someone
you don't even ask questions,
you just move. Holy Spirit says
something, you say, okay, but
you know Lord, you know, you see
me. Eroi, eroi, the God that
sees me. He sees you, that's why
he's giving you the instruction.
He knows you can do it. You see
me like this, eroi. You are
building infrastructure through
obedience, full obedience.
Amen. Full obedience. Building
infrastructure through
enlargement of your heart.
Whatever cannot sit pretty in
your heart, you can never have
it. Some of you, if they send 10
million to you now, you will
faint. So God is even trying to
protect you. I don't want this
girl to faint. Let's just give
her 5. Glory to God. And you are
here trusting God for billions,
and yet your heart is not even
enlarged to take one, and you
are trusting God for billions.
Billions! Oh God, send in the
billions! It's not like they
don't want to give you the
billions. Your heart can't take
it. You will collapse. Praise
God. So build infrastructure,
build spiritual infrastructure,
enlarge your hearts. Sojourning
in the land of promise, do it
intentionally. Glory to God.
You've not traveled out of the
country, take excursion to the
airport. Do it, it does
something to your mind. Glory to
God. Be intentional about it.
Don't say, 'Kesara sera,
whatever will be, will be.'
Whatever will be does not used
to be. It doesn't happen. Be
intentional about it. You want
to build a mega company. Have
you visited someone that has
one? Have you tried to have
conversation with the person?
Have you been around greatness
so that they can strengthen your
mind, they can expand your mind?
No, you are in your room. Oh
God, I want a 2 billion worth of
company. Azao. Enlarge your
heart. What cannot enter your
heart not just enter, sit
pretty, be comfortable.
Whatever can— whatever your
heart cannot comfortably take,
your hand cannot touch it. It's
a principle. Your hand cannot
touch it. So some— it means that
some of you even need to go and
remove the limit on your— you
are trusting God for billions.
So the same person that was
praying for billions in church,
the highest money you can
receive is 200,000, and you say,
okay, I didn't say anything.
Glory to God. And billions, oh
God, billions! You can't receive
more than 4 million. Even the
angels are confused and like,
what is working? What is man
that thou art mindful of him?
God, what is all this? See me
holding billions here, this boy
cannot even take it.
Hallelujah! Another way you
build infrastructure is by
developing your mind. So, so
many spiritual people neglect
their mind. You neglect them,
and your mind is a God's
intention is a mediator. It's an
infrastructure that God created,
is a mediator. The way you
interpret the things of the
spirit to your natural world is
through your mind. That's why it
seems like some people will read
the Bible and explain it, and
you're like, ah, it's not that
Holy Spirit gave them another
inspiration. The way their mind
interpreted it is quite
different because it's a
developed mind. Develop your
mind. They call you for an
interview, you are not well
read. You do— you don't— they're
asking, oh, so you know what
this person said in this book?
Oh, let's just, let's just,
let's just move past it. Glory
to God. Let's just, let's just
go. Develop your mind. You don't
know when your breakthrough will
come. Develop your mind. Be
ready. Build structure. If you
are trusting God for this
harvest, then you have to
develop your mind. Develop your
mind intentionally. Tell me the
last time some of you read is,
is, um, university days. And
when you leave, you're like,
ha, if I touch book again, make
I bend. If I touch book again.
That's why you are where you
are. God wants to promote you.
To be honest, he wants to
promote you, but you need to
represent him well. You can't
say you are a Christian, they
bring you on national TV and you
are yanni nukoto. By your first
3 sentences, they know that this
is empty. It's not just by the
spirit. Don't just do everything
by the spirit. Don't worry, we
just get it, we just do it by
the spirit. Develop your mind.
That's how you build
infrastructure. Be intentional
about it. Stop engaging in
activities. Stop watching
Telemundo. Telemundo.
Telemundo. Amen. They will dull
the efficacy of your mind. They
will dull it. Something that you
already know how it will end by
the title— the— what's that?
The Wicked Stepmother. If you
see The Wicked Stepmother,
don't you already know how the
story will end? That the mother
will be wicked to the baby.
That's how it will end. And you
will still watch and say, ah,
it's dulling your mind.
Installing your mind. Read
books. Hallelujah! The quality
of your mind is the quality of
your life. The quality of your
mind is the quality of your
life. You can't grow past what
you don't know now. Amen. Glory
to God. So the man of God has
helped us with solid materials
to build capacity for the
harvest. He has talked about
mercy, the intervention of God's
mercy. Some of what we enjoy
It's just the mercy of God,
because God is like, this guy
has stayed too long in this
class, let's just, let's just
have mercy. He thought on the
mercy of God. Amen. Thought on
favor. Favor. Somebody say
favor. Hallelujah. Say favor.
And look, God is not a God that
is not— he's not just able,
he's willing. He wants to.
He's more willing than you are.
That billions, he knows that
when it gets to your hand,
you're a good steward. But you
need infrastructure. He's
willing. He's not just a God of
waste. And the recent one the
man of God talked about is
favor. If you listen to the
morning prayer, he talked about
favor. And you have to
understand how favor works.
See, fastest route to hard labor
is a man that does not work in
favor. You'll be suffering. You
don't have favor, you're not
working, you will— the journey
will be long because favor is
the cheat code for a believer.
Amen. Favor establishes us.
Bible says that you have caused
my mountain to stand strong.
That's why they cannot move you
anyhow, because by favor your
mountain has stand strong.
Amen. Glory to God. So favor,
favor, you can't do— you can't
move ahead In fact, Pastor used
to say, your entire lifetime,
you cannot catch up with God's
plan for your life. You need
favor, you need something that
will speed you up. So if you
think you can just be doing it
like Esau, just be doing it like
Esau, I'm going to the bush when
Jacob is here, already collected
the goat meat for his mother,
has received blessing, and you
still want to go. No, no, no,
no, no, no, it's hard work. You
have to be hardworking. Good.
You go tse. You go tse for that
hard work, eh. Hallelujah.
Praise God forevermore.
Amen. Favor establishes. Favor
establishes. Hallelujah. The
favor of God is a shield of
deliverance. The favor of God is
a shield of deliverance. Bible
says you have encompassed me
with favor like a shield. So
people are supporting you even
though you are not there.
That's the man working in favor.
People want to defend you.
People just love you. They just
want to do things for you.
They're like, no, no, no, no,
no, when it gets to this person,
no, no, I can't take that. They
want to defend your righteous
cause. Even sometimes when you
are actually guilty, they just
want to defend you. Amen.
Glory to God. Favor is a shield
of deliverance. It's a shield of
protection. A shield of
protection. Amen.
Bible says the smell of my son
is like a field that the Lord
has blessed. People come around
you and they just— there's just
something about you that they
want to— they just want to
favor. They just want to— they
just want to do something for
you. Just imagine living that
kind of— you, you are living and
you are not experiencing things
like that. People just look at
you and say, let me just buy
this thing for this person.
Amen. However, there are
misconceptions around favor,
very funny misconceptions. And
one of them is that you can be
yourself. You know what I mean
by be yourself? In spite of you,
God does not look at me, he will
just favor me. It's a very wrong
misconception. God does not
shine his light on mediocrity.
He does not shine. It doesn't
happen, especially if you call
yourself a believer. He doesn't
shine his light on mediocrity.
You know why that your tailoring
business is not global? You
know, because when you sew, one
side is like this, and you're
like, no, no, no, no, wear the
wig. If you wear the wig of the
person that the picture you
showed me, if you wear it, it
will fit. No, no, no, no, it's
because of the way you are
standing. And God is like, this
girl is not ready. And you are
praying with spotlights,
spotlights. No, he doesn't shine
his light on mediocrity. So it's
a wrong misconception to think
that you can be anyhow, do
anyhow, talk anyhow, behave
anyhow, dress anyhow, but yet
the favor of God will be working
for you. They give you clothes
to launder, you murdered it.
You murdered the— glory to God.
Amen. You murdered it instead.
You have good products, you have
poor package. Because the God of
Excellence. So you are— you,
you need to focus on the right
thing at the right time. Focus
on excellence first, then God
will shine his spotlight. Just
as I am, just as I am. Oh God,
anyhow, you, you, you, you baked
cake, the cake is not caking,
feels hard, it just feels hard.
Like, you're like, shake it,
and you want spotlight. They're
like, please refer me, oh,
refer me to— even your friend,
I say they will refer you, they
know that they will not refer
you. You are going for an
interview, you are poorly
dressed, poorly read.
They're asking you questions,
you say, skip, skip, skip,
skip, skip. Amen. Hallelujah.
You don't have to have much to
look good. Or look good, look
like the future that you are
going into. Look good.
See, God is He's the only person
that looks at the heart. It's
when you want to go and submit
interview to God, or you want to
submit your CV to God, to God
directly, that it doesn't need
what you are looking like. But
you, you, you, you are, you are,
you are so rumpled, people
around you are like, no, no,
it's the favor, the favor of God
is upon me, they will not see
it, they won't see it, it's just
the favor of God. No, no, you
are wrong, you are wrong, you
are not representing God well.
Hallelujah! And that brings me
to my next misconception, which
is to assume that favor with God
automatically means favor with
men. You lie! You what?
You lie! You have to convert it.
Convert favor. Anywhere in the
scripture that God talks about
favor, he talks about it in
connection with men. Amen.
Media, can you please project
Luke 2:52? In fact,
how we know that a man is highly
favored is how men treat him.
That's how we know. Oh no, this
man is favored, this man is
blessed. Is how men treat you.
And so, oh no, I'm accepted in
the beloved. So you will convert
it, you convert it, you convert
that favor with God with men.
No man can tell me anything. No
man can tell me anything. I have
favor with God. If I'm accepted
with God, who are you? Ah,
glory to God. You must learn how
to connect with the favor of
men. Luke 2:52, is it there?
Luke 2:52, is it there? Okay.
And Jesus increased in wisdom
and stature and in favor with
God and men.
It does not matter what's the
point. It's favor, favor,
favor. He's around me like— and
that's all that matters. You
need favor with men. You need
people, critical people, to like
you in this life. Hallelujah.
So how do we know a man that is
working in favor with men? How
do we know? Number 1,
acceptance. Divine likability.
They just like you. It matters.
Who likes you? Please don't join
the cancel culture. It doesn't
matter who likes you. Does not
matter. So far God has liked
you. God is not living here on
earth. He's not living here on
earth. Divine likability. You
need people to accept you. You
need people to accept your
product. You need people to
accept your— everything you are
doing, you need acceptance. You
need acceptance. Hallelujah!
Your business must be accepted.
Your ministry to thrive must be
accepted. You need divine-like
ability. Glory to
God. Bible says in Esther 2:15,
and Esther obtained favor in the
sights of all of them that
looked upon her. You need favor
in the sight of men. You need,
you need this favor. If not,
you'll be slow in life. Things
will be dragging. Things that
should naturally take 1 year,
10 years you are still there.
You need this favor. You need
men to accept you. You need men
that play significant role in
your life. You've not met them
yet, but yet when you meet them,
they just want to open their
heart to you. You need it.
Bible says, and Jesus, even
Jesus, because he needs his
ministry to be accepted, even
Jesus Bible says he works in
wisdom and in stature and in
favor with God and men. Glory to
God! Glory to God! The disciples
were praising God and they were
having favor with all the
people. So you need favor. You
need favor. Tell your neighbor,
I need this favor. I don't know
about you, I need that favor. I
need people to accept what I'm
doing all over the world. All
over the world. Some of you are
deceived that what they are
doing, if I bring it to church,
they'll just buy it. If you take
it out of church and go, have
they accepted it? You need this
favor. Hallelujah! Another way
you know a man that God has
highly favored is access. They
just find you trustworthy. They
want to open their loins to you.
Glory to God! This is when God
gives you access to people,
places, circles, and opportunity
that ordinarily they are beyond
your reach. Ordinarily, you
wouldn't have gotten there in 20
years. It just opens that door.
Their heart is just open to you,
and they're like, um, I think
you should follow me to
Australia. I just want to show
you some things. Normally, you
know that if you save up, if you
save, Australia is far from
you. Glory to God. And then you
just meet people, I just want
bring you in. They're just— they
just want to bring you into
their circle. They don't feel a
certain way about it. There's
something about it. I feel like
you belong here. Let's bring him
in. He belongs here. You are not
there, but they just feel like
you fit in. You need that favor
in your life. I know today is
all possibility service. We
activate that favor today.
Glory to God. Glory to God.
When people give you
opportunities that are beyond
you You— that's the only way you
can catch up. That's the only
way you can ever catch up with
destiny. If you think you want
to be doing your life
systematically— when I, when I
finish secondary school, I will
go to university. When I go to
university, I will now serve.
When I serve, I will now—
what's, what's the next one? I
will now work. After working, I
will now marry. When I marry,
my mind will now come. I will
not be working. Asu will first
of all burst that bubble that
you are still in school. At
maybe you use— you are supposed
to use 4 years, you're using 8
years already. Before I'm,
before I'm 22, thereabout, I
should be done. I should be
done. And Asu is keeping you in
school. You're already 27. Your
service is not coming through
fast. They've not posted me.
They've not posted me. They
posted me. You have to wait
again. And you are moving
towards States. That's how life
is kind of designed. It will
always be bad in the world.
It's only for those that are in
Christ that is different. For it
will always be bad. So you need
to activate this favor. It
doesn't happen like that too.
Is it Nollywood? They are
deceiving us. It doesn't happen
like that. It doesn't— ask
people that have gone ahead of
you. Favor market, go and ask
them whether there is favor in
the marketplace. It's only for
the believers and the ones that
enforce that favor. Hallelujah!
Glory to God! You need men.
Bible says in 1 Kings, he said,
I will loose the loins of—
Isaiah 45— I will loose the
loins of kings. Not just
ordinary men, kings, people in
highly, highly placed people.
They are interested in you,
they are interested in your
business, they are interested in
your product. They want to help
you, they want to bring you in.
Don't say, oh, let the rich
don't cook with the poor, so
let's not even— no, no. Favor
bridges that gap. Favor bridges
that gap. They bring you into
their circle.
Hallelujah! Glory to God! Glory
to God! How many of you want
that kind of favor? I want that
kind of favor because you begin
to hear information. You now
wonder, so People know this kind
of things. So this kind of
information really exists.
Somebody was telling me about a
course, very, very simple
course, nothing so complicated,
a course you just need to learn.
And even me, I don't know the
course because the person just
said it's a course. So if you
just do that course, is just 6
months or 8 months thereabouts,
that if you just have the
certification of this course,
there's no way— no oil company
will reject you. In fact, they
are looking for people like
that. They are still looking for
people like that till now. If
you come into circles like that,
that's when you get to know
things like that. You just be
there, okay, what can I do? The
business, let me start a makeup
stuff, let me be selling on
this, let me be— that's the only
thing that will come to your
mind because that's the
information that you have access
to. If you start selling akara
now, before you open shop, you
now had pop-off and buns.
That's the only thing that will
come to your mind. And there are
untapped resources, untapped
opportunities. Amen. You need
this favor. You need this favor.
Another way is generosity of
men. This is when men just want
to give to you. They just look
at you and like, oh, what do you
do? Oh, I sell this. Um, if I
give you 50 million, what can
you do with that? That kind of—
you see the way it shock you,
that kind. And you're like,
wait, ah, wait, ah, sir. 50
million. Maybe you are selling
honey or you are selling
slippers and it's okay. What can
you do with 50 million? Okay,
if I give you 100 million, can
you do something out of it? I
can do something out of it.
Amen. You need that. You will be
slow in life if you think you
can just— you can plot the way
your life would go. When I do
this, I will not do this. By the
time I start this business, at
least one year into this
business, I'll now boom. Yeah,
it doesn't happen like that.
Glory to God. Glory to God.
When men find you compelling
enough to invest in, you don't
have to do too much. They just
look at you and like, okay,
talk to me about your business.
And you're talking like, oh,
that's interesting. Okay,
let's, let's, let's, let's do
200 million. Amen. Because see
All the money that you are— your
dream money in life, if they
pack all of you's dream money
now, is in somebody's account.
God is not sending money from
heaven again. All the money you
need, all the resources that you
need, is on earth, is with men.
Your own future is somebody's
past. If you have like, have
like 30 billion now, That was
somebody's past, long time ago,
sitting pretty in their account.
You just need the connection.
You just need those that have to
connect with you. Recently we
found out that some
organizations, in fact, if they
don't release the money,
government will tax them. So
they are actually waiting for
people that they will release
the money to. And here we are
praying for the money that they
are really— they just, just get
people so that we can give them
this money. And it's not small
money. Get people, get pictures,
that's all we need. If they
don't release that money,
they'll be in trouble. So they
must release it in hundreds of
millions of dollars. In this
life that we are, so all this,
oh God, I need money. You just
need the right connection. You
just need people that will hold
your hand. You just need people
that will find you appealing
enough to invest in you. You
think the way you are doing
business is how they do
business? No, that's not how
they do it. Let money hit that
business, then you will know.
You begin, you restructure. You
will need time. You, they give
it to me, okay, I need to go to
Dubai first, or Maldives, to
think about how I want to now do
this business. You are still
holding pen and paper. Okay, so
when we— 50,000 came in,
expenditure 8,000, so my profits
will not— you need, you need,
you need speed. You need speed.
Hallelujah! There was a lawyer
that did a job for a woman. He
doesn't know the woman.
Somebody just introduced him as,
okay, this, this woman can do
this thing for you, this man can
do this thing for you. And they
just did it. So something very
simple now, very— it's not even
a court case or anything, it's
very simple thing. And then he
says, because he even thought
that the woman was a, you know,
I think the woman sound— you
know, there's a way they sound.
They say, ah, how much is that?
Too much. That they don't sound
like that. Okay, that's fine,
send your account number. They
sound like me, like this. Amen.
So the lawyer said, I think he
has perceived that this woman is
comfortable. So she just said
something that normally you
should do 150K for. Said, Mom,
it's fine if you can give me
500K, it's fine. And the man
said, okay, that's fine, send
your details. And the woman sent
him 11 million. Real life.
I know the person it happened
to. 11 million. I know that,
ma, you made a mistake, ma. So
don't you know what to do with
the rest? That was the question.
I said, yes, I know what I did.
Don't you know what to do with
the rest? That kind of favor is
what facilitates you in life.
So if you sit and think you can
be doing calculation and I will
not get there, you'll be slow.
You need escalated favor.
Hallelujah! Glory to God!
Generosity of men— they just
want to open their alabaster box
for you. So come, come, what do
you do? What do you do? What do
you— they just want to release
that money to you. They just
find you trustworthy. That kind
of favor is resting mightily
upon us today in the name of
Jesus. Glory to God! Another way
you know is compelled kindness.
Compelled kindness. These ones,
they don't need to like you.
They don't need to like you.
You know that one is divine
likability. This one, they don't
need to like you. They'll just
be compelled to promote you.
Pastor shared the story of a
man. This boss hates him,
obviously. Anything is out.
Amen. and there was a time that
they needed somebody to promote.
Now the promotion is not, oh,
from assistant manager to
manager. It's like from janitor
in the army to manager. And then
when they were talking, oh, so
we need somebody that will
replace this person since you
are going— this same boss that
hates him, let's just use him.
Just, just, it just came to his
mind, he just recommended him.
Amen. And then when he met him,
said, you know what, I'm
leaving, and then I recommended
you to replace me. And the guy
was like, sir, you recommended
me? You that hates me? You hate
me so much, you know, you can't
even stand me, and you are
recommending me? Say, when I was
even just thinking about it,
there was no person that— there
was no name that came to my
mind. It was just your name. I
just said it. And then he said,
come on, get out of my office,
get out of my office. Bam! You
don't need them to like you.
Compelled kindness. Compelled
kindness. Compelled kindness.
You go for an interview, the
boss already saw you, she walked
in or he walked in, and then the
interviewer is saying— when they
brought in the list, they say,
oh no, no, we got— interviewer
already said, no, no, no, we
can't pick this one. And the
boss said, who is this person?
Oh, she's Ayomide. Ayomide, I
think I saw her. Pick her. 'Ma,
no, no, no, she's not
qualified.' I said, 'Pick her.'
Compelled kindness. The boss
might not even set eyes on the
person until the girl leaves
that place. That's compelled
kindness. That's people not
liking you, but yet they will
facilitate what you are doing.
They will bless your righteous
cause. Hallelujah! Glory to
God! Proverbs 16:7 says, 'When a
man's way pleases the Lord, he
maketh even his enemies to be at
peace with him.' So now there's
a clause. You begin to think,
oh, I need to please the Lord.
We are already pleasing to God.
We are righteous. Every
righteous man is pleasing to
God. So don't start to do, oh,
I need to be pleasing to God
before my enemies. That's what
people used to think. Glory to
God! When the ways of the man
please the Lord, he maketh his
enemies to be at peace with him.
Even those that don't like you
will favor your righteous cause.
Hallelujah! I remember when I
was in school then, my lecturer—
structure. If you, if you're a
construction person, you know
what structure is. It's our
nightmare. I just wrote the exam
yesterday. I'm writing another
exam today. You met me, another
exam that is not structure. You
called me and say, Lawrence,
you failed structure. I'm like,
sir, I wrote this exam just
yesterday. Are you saying that
you've marked it? Obviously I
know what he's doing. No, no,
you failed it. I told you you
failed. Are you going to be
arguing with me? You failed. I
said, okay, sir. And then he now
said, anyway, you know what your
mates— go and meet your mates.
They will tell you what they do
if you want to pass this course.
I already know. I don't need to
meet my— I know what they do. I
just said, no worries, I will
write it. Say, eh, you write it?
I will write it. You are going
to write. What if you fail the
course? If I fail the course, I
will write it again. Is it that
thing that you want me to do? I
will not do it. That's you,
that's you, it's your cup of
tea, it's your cup of tea. If
you spend how many years in this
school, it's not anybody's
business. No problems, I will
write it. The following year, I
rewrite, I rewrote it, and then
I passed it to the glory of God.
If you're not, if you're an
architect, you know what it
means to pass structure. But
that's not the juicy part. I
went back to school, and then I
think I went to do something,
already left, already graduated.
And one woman, one of our
lecturers, actually came to me
and said, oh, Dr. Adeyemi, he
says, uh-uh, Lawrence, how are
you? It's people like you that
we want to, you know, you need
to come and speak to these
people. And then the same
lecturer was saying, oh yes,
yes, yes, yes, yes, she, pick
her, let her be the one to speak
to the people. He obviously
doesn't like me. Obviously,
because I'm not playing to his
tune, but he recommended me.
That's, that is where men are
compelled to like you. So don't
be in it, don't really, really—
when somebody you are trying to
show love to somebody and the
person is wicked to you, don't
mind. Your own is to favor me.
You keep your likeness, just
favor me. Hallelujah. And Esau
ran— Genesis 33:4— Esau ran to
meet him and embraced him and
fell on his neck and kissed him.
You now know what Jacob did to
the guy, right? You know what
Jacob did to that guy. Stole his
bed and ran away. Ah,
glory to God. And when Esau saw
him, compelled— he has no
choice, he has no choice—
he ran to meet him, he embraced
him, fell on his neck.
Hallelujah. And I will give you
these people favor in the sight
of the Egyptians, and every
woman shall borrow of her
neighbor jewels of silver,
jewels of gold and raiment.
People that just lost their
children, people that are
mourning, that are mourning. Is
that the kind of person that
wants to be generous towards you
and know that you are the cause
of that mourning? In one day,
all the firstborn, including
firstborn of ants, animals,
died. They were mourning, they
were in pain. And God says, go
and meet them, they will give
you everything. Weeping people.
Go and meet them. So an Egyptian
and Israelite woman said,
Madam, I've been eyeing that,
your gold. He's like, my gold?
I'll bring it for you. I'll be
nice, I will bring it for you.
Just pack everything, just go.
Morning people. So it means that
the emotions of men does not
even matter in this case. They
just will be compelled to be
kind to you. Hallelujah! Glory
to God! Glory to God! Glory to
God! Bible says they gave them
jewels of silver, gold.
Treasures. You meet somebody and
they say, you look like my
daughter. You don't look like
the daughter, it's favor. Hey,
when favor is at work, people
start to see things though. You
look like my daughter, you know,
my daughter is not— she's very,
you know, established, but I'm
looking for someone that I can
just pour into. I have some
trust funds because you look
like her, um, send me your
details. I just want to bless
you before I go. And you receive
the alarm, not a lot, you know
there's a lot, there's alarm.
The alarm just land on your
phone, boom, your phone almost
vibrated. That kind of escalated
favor, you need it. If no,
you'll be slow. You need it.
You can't calculate the journey
of your life. When I do this,
I'll do this, I'll do this.
When I now start this business,
at least by now I should— you
are not factoring God's favor.
You are not factoring God's
favor. You will be slow. You
will be slow. Glory to God.
That's even if you get there at
all. Or maybe you get there when
you already have been building
this since I was 10, now I am,
I'm 87. Uh-uh.
And when they calculate your net
worth, is one 22-year-old boy's
past. Hallelujah. Entrustment.
Number 5, this is when people
place authority,
responsibility, resources, or
something valuable into your
hands because they trust you to
manage it. They've not met you
before, but they just trust you.
That's what happened to Joseph.
The only thing Joseph doesn't
have access to is the wife, and
even the wife wanted to throw
You see the way this favor is
working? Glory to God. Even a
wife— now Potiphar did not hand
his wife over to Joseph. The
wife wants to hand herself over
to Joseph. Oh,
glory to God. Entrustment.
Genesis 39:4, it says, and
Joseph found grace in his sight,
and he made him overseer over
his house and all that he had
put in his hands. Joseph carried
this favor so much Even in
prison, he was the captain of
the prisoners. As a slave,
captain of slaves. And from
prison, captain. He carried that
grace so much. When people look
at you, they just think that you
can lead. They just want to
trust you. Not that, oh, you go
to the back, go to the back, go
to the back, go to the back.
When they just see you, they're
like, no, no, you look like
somebody that can really do.
You cannot do. You really
cannot, you really have to go
and take courses to do it. But
when they see, they just want to
favor you. They just feel like,
yes, you can do it. That kind of
favor, entrustment. Glory to
God. And the keeper of the
prison committed to Joseph's
hand all the prisoners. A
prisoner, you committed all the
prisoners to a prisoner. Favor.
Somebody say favor. Glory to
God. And Pharaoh said unto
Joseph, see, I have set thee
over all the land of Egypt. You
just joined as an intern and
they already seen you as a
leadership spec. You just joined
in, but this person has
something that I like. That's
something they can't touch it,
they can't see it, they can't
feel it. They just know that
there's something about this
person. I think you should come
and assist me in my office. And
then from then, oversee
everything. Favor.
Not that they will look at you
and they just want to naturally
put you at the back. Join,
join, join, join this way. Just
join this queue. You need that
favor. Hallelujah! Glory to
God! Preferential treatment.
Life is never fair. No, no,
life is never fair. It won't be.
Preferential treatment,
exclusive treatments. If life
was fair, God will not be
telling us that he will give
other people's life for our own.
It's not— his life is designed
not to be fair. So if you want
to stay on the fair spectrum,
oh no, go, no, no, let him go,
Lord, no, it's not— you are
holier than the Holy Spirit, oh
no, no, no. Even God says I will
give another person's life for
your life, but you, you want to
be fair. They are treating you
specially at work. You don't
know that it's the favor of God.
You are saying, sir, I want to
have some conversation with you.
Amen. I see the way— I know you
like me. I see the way you treat
me, but I'm just suggesting if
you can show the same kind— what
is your business? What is your
business? If they can show the
same kindness to this person,
but they saw the person. What's
your business? And if favor is
working, you need wisdom. You
need wisdom. They are treating
you specially at work and you
are getting uncomfortable with
uncomfortable with being treated
specially. You cannot sit pretty
with it. You cannot be
comfortable with being— you
cannot stay in the middle.
You're already afraid. Oh, they
will not be my friend. I don't,
I don't know. I don't— they will
not feel good about— what's your
business now? You're carrying
favor. You have to be conscious
of it. You have to be conscious
of it. In fact, when they don't
do it to you, you should check
yourself. When you walk into a
place and they don't naturally
love you and the boss does not
pick interest in you, check
yourself. You need to pray. You
need to pray. Hallelujah! Are
you getting blessed this
morning? Hallelujah! And this
Daniel was preferred above the
presidents and princes. Because
an excellent spirit was in him,
and the king thought to set him
over the whole realm.
Entrustment. And the
king loved Esther. Please, is
Esther prettier than all the
women? What is with Esther that
is different from every other
woman? It's just favor, the
selective goodness of God.
Bible says he loved Esther above
all other ones. Above— do you
know how many kings, how many
queens that these men married
back then? Well, he loved
Hallelujah! I don't know whether
I just want one of those signs
of favor. Maybe your own is just
to, Lord, leave likability,
just give me access. But for me,
I want everything, everything.
And you are going to be
enforcing it today. Today is all
possibilities on the— anything
is possible here. Glory to God!
Thank you for listening.
For inquiries, contact us
using our helpline
+234-8104-544689.
Go in this mind.